<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Tuller-con 2021</title>
    <link>https://alondmnt.com/HZ-meeting2021/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Tuller-con 2021</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 18:47:54 +0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alondmnt.com/HZ-meeting2021/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Venue</title>
      <link>https://alondmnt.com/HZ-meeting2021/posts/venue/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 18:47:54 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alondmnt.com/HZ-meeting2021/posts/venue/</guid>
      <description>The mini-conference will take place in the
Rosenblatt Auditorium,
Wolfson Building for Computer and Software Engineering,
Tel Aviv University.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Posters</title>
      <link>https://alondmnt.com/HZ-meeting2021/posts/posters/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jul 2021 21:06:57 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alondmnt.com/HZ-meeting2021/posts/posters/</guid>
      <description>Download the poster abstract booklet.
First Session (11:45)    Poster number Poster presenter Poster title     1 Stav Carmel Ezra Modeling the effect of rRNA-mRNA interactions and mRNA folding on mRNA translation in organelles   2 Shimshi Atar Effect of human microbiome supplementation on metabolic disease and other conditions.   3 Nataly Makarenkov Circulating Micro-RNAs As Biomarkers of Visceral Obesity-Related Adipose Tissue Disease (OrAD)   4 Shani Cohen Machine Learning for prediction of sRNA-mRNA interactions   5 matan arbel, shaked bergman Evolutionary Stability Optimizer (ESO): A Novel Approach to Identify and Avoid Mutational Hotspots in DNA Sequences while Inducing High Expression Levels   6 Alma Davidson Automatic modeling of tissue specificity of viruses   7 David Shallom Accelerating whole cell simulations of mRNA translation using a dedicated hardware   8 Mahua Bhattacharya Non-optimal codon usage determines the protein level dynamics during cell-cycle   9 Sharon Bader Computational Modeling of the effect of miRNA binding sites distribution on mRNA stability   10 Sophie Vinokour Determinants of Efficient Modulating of Ribosomal Traffic Jams   11 Larissa Fine Engineering and testing the translation process in prokaryotes via examination of plasmids library, TCP-seq and ribosome profiling   12 Tal Gutman Estimating the Predictive Power of Silent Mutations on Cancer Classification and Prognosis   13 Michael Peeri Analysis of selection on mRNA secondary structure strength in protein-coding sequences within conserved protein families   14 Olawumi Giwa The experimental validation of gene-gene fusions as a diagnostic tool for the detection of Glioblastoma Multiforme (GBM).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Agenda</title>
      <link>https://alondmnt.com/HZ-meeting2021/posts/agenda/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jul 2021 09:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alondmnt.com/HZ-meeting2021/posts/agenda/</guid>
      <description>   Time Presenter Title     9:30 – 9:45 Tamir Tuller Welcome &amp;amp; introduction   9:45 – 10:30 Dmitrij Frishman, TUM The evolution of polyproline motifs   10:30 – 10:50 Shir Bahiri, TAU Modeling of translation re-initiation in prokaryotes based on the analyses of heterologous and endogenous operons.   10:50 – 11:00  Coffee break   11:00 – 11:20 Rachel Kolodny, Haifa University Studying codon patterns with deep networks   11:20 – 11:45  Poster highlights   11:45 – 12:15  First poster session + break   12:15 – 12:40  Lunch break   12:40 – 13:25 Amnon Horovitz, WIS Chaperonin nano-machines: allostery and function   13:25 – 13:50  Poster highlights   13:50 – 14:25  Second poster session + break   14:25 – 14:45 Nataly Makarenkov, BGU Circulating Micro-RNAs As Biomarkers of Visceral Obesity-Related Adipose Tissue Disease (OrAD)   14:45 – 15:05 Zohar Zafrir, TAU Rational Design of Synthetic Zika Virus Vaccines Based on Computational Models   15:05 – 15:25 Sumit Mukherjee, BIU Immunoinformatics analysis for identification of evolutionary conserved immunodominant epitopes in SARS-CoV-2   15:25 – 16:00  Summary + Tuller Lab get together    </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
